Drew Middleton Papers
Drew Middleton Papers
1935-1967
Middleton, Drew, 1913-1990.
1.25 linear ft.
Foreign correspondent and author. Collection contains manuscripts of four of Middleton's books including his first, Struggle for Germany, published in 1949.
2741075
Biographical History
Drew Middleton (1913-1990) was a reporter for the Associated Press and the New York Times, noted for his combat reports as Foreign Correspondent for the Times during World War II, and his coverage and analysis of postwar Europe and the cold war. He is author of more than a dozen books on military affairs, postwar diplomacy, and foreign policy.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Drew Middleton Papers consist of Memorabilia and Writings.
Memorabilia, donated separately, contains photographs, a clipping, and a postcard.
Writings contains manuscripts for four of Middleton's books. There are three drafts of America's Stake in Asia (1967), two drafts and a set of galleys for The Atlantic Community (1965), one draft of Crisis in the West (1965), and one draft of Struggle for Germany (1949, his first book). There are also two items of correspondence with his editors, one relating to each of the first two titles.
Arrangement of the Collection
Writings are in alphabetical order by book title.
Related Material
The library has published editions of many of Middleton's books, including Our Share of Night: A Personal Narrative of the War Years. Please refer to to locate these items.
Separated Material
A published copy of The Atlantic Community has been sent to Rare Books for cataloging.
Subject and Genre Headings
Historians; Journalism; Military history; Middleton, Drew, 1913-1990.; Foreign correspondents -- Europe.; International Relations -- Asia.; World politics -- 1955-1965.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Personal narratives.; Europe -- History -- 1918-1945.; Europe -- Politics and government -- 1918-1945.; Asia -- Foreign relations -- United States.; United States -- Foreign relations -- Asia.; North Atlantic Region -- Politics and government.; North Atlantic Region -- Strategic aspects.; Germany -- Politics and government -- 1945-1990.; Correspondence.; Galley proofs.; Manuscripts for publication.; Photographs.; Typescripts.; Authors.; Historians.; Military historians.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Drew Middleton, 1967, 1968, 1971.
Memorabilia folder, gift of Aline Archambault, 2015.
Inventory
- Memorabilia
  - Miscellaneous, 1935; 1945,; undated (Box 1)
    Gift of Aline Archambault, 2015.
    This folder contains a photograph of Drew Middleton, a photograph of a meeting between Franklin D. Roosevelt and Winston Churchill with Middleton in background, a postcard with the image of the Onondaga Hotel in Syracuse, N.Y. that was addressed to Middleton's sister Audrey, and a brief New York Times article dated 28 May 1945 about the American graves at Saint Laurent sur Mer in Normandy written by Drew Middleton.
- Writings
  - America's Stake in Asia (1967)
    - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Draft A, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Draft B, appears to be identical to Draft A, down to the same handwritten corrections; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Draft C, incorporates corrections on previous drafts (Box 1)
  - The Atlantic Community (1965)
    - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 2)
    - Draft, 10 folders (Box 2)
    - Publisher's copy of draft, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Final typescript (Box 2)
    - Gallerys, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Crisis in the West (1965)
    - Draft (Box 2)
  - Struggle for Germany (1949)
    - Draft (Box 3)